# **Ananya Agarwal**

+91 9634215260

☑ ananya.agarwal18@outlook.com

Noida

in ananya-agarwal-1555201b6

ananya1898

## Summary \_

Automation Test Engineer experienced in software development processes and optimal testing strategies. Currently contributing to an in-house automation framework with a focus on ease of configuration, usability, and live tracking. Helps teams produce exceptional products by providing in-depth quality assurance support. Known for clear communication, multitasking skills, organizational strengths, and attention to detail.

## Education

### **Bachelor of Technology, Electronics And Communication**

2017 - 2021

· Jaypee Institute of Information Technology, Noida

• CGPA: 8.2

**Delhi Public School** 

2012 - 2016

• Senior Secondary School, CGPA: 8.3 (2014-2016)

• Secondary School, CGPA: 10 (2012-2014)

## **Experience**

#### Ion Group, Automation Engineer

Noida, India Aug. 2021 - Present

Demonstrated expertise as the sole leader in automating testing procedures for legacy software
and infrastructure components, ensuring the high-quality deliverables for leading banks like
UBS, Scotia, Mitsubishi, and Pierpont.

- Successfully progressed from a graduate role to leading the Quality Assurance team, showcasing leadership and proficiency in automation testing over the past 3 years.
- Spearheaded efforts to reduce the monthly testing cycle work by 50% to an efficient automated process, showcasing commitment to optimizing workflows.
- Contributing to the development of an in-house automation framework with a focus on ease of configuration, usability, and live tracking capabilities.

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions, Program Analyst Trainee

India

• Developed strong problem-solving skills by troubleshooting complex issues during the internship period.

• Gained valuable experience working within an agile development environment, utilizing Scrum methodologies.

Feb. 2021 - Aug. 2021

## **Projects** \_

- Filtering and Detection of Hoax news using Machine Learning
- Triple Threshold Statistical Detection filter for removing high density random-valued impulse noise in images using Python.

#### Skills

Python, Java, Selenium, Junit, Git, SQL, Bash, RobotFrameWork, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Jira, Scrum, Agile

#### Interests

Swimming, Playing Guitar, Travelling, Feeding and Caring for Stray Dogs, Reading